The Windermere Children is a drama, war, history
film directed by Michael Samuels.
The story of the pioneering project to rehabilitate child survivors
of the Holocaust on the shores of Lake Windermere.
Oscar Friedmann, played by Thomas Kretschmann.
Marie Paneth, played by Romola Garai.
Jock Lawrence, played by Iain Glen.
Leonard Montefiore, played by Tim McInnerny.
Berish Lerner, played by Marcel Sabat.
Georg Lauer, played by Philipp Christopher.
The Windermere Children is a 2020 British biographical drama television
film written by Simon Block and directed by Michael Samuels.
Based on the experience of child survivors of the Holocaust, it follows the children and staff of a camp set up on the Calgarth Estate  in Troutbeck Bridge,
near Lake Windermere, England, where the survivors were helped to rehabilitate, rebuild their lives, and integrate into the British society.
The film was produced by Simon Block as 'executive producer' with Nancy
Bornat as factual producer and Ben Evans as development producer.
The film first aired on BBC Two in January 2020.
The film explores themes of childhood trauma, based on true story,
holocaust (shoah) survivor, kindness, compassion.
The tone is emotional.